mfe.govt.nz 2019-07-15

# Privacy statement | Ministry for the Environment

Read our privacy statement for information on this website.

This privacy statement applies to any personal and other information collected on the Ministry for the Environment’s website at [www.mfe.govt.nz](https://www.mfe.govt.nz/).

Like most website owners, we collect statistical information about your visit to help us improve our website. This information is used for no other purpose and all users are anonymous. We collect information on:

  * IP addresses
  * search terms
  * pages accessed and links clicked
  * dates and times of visits
  * the immediate previous site visited
  * operating systems
  * web browsers.

You may browse and access information contained within the website without providing any personal information. Where you voluntarily provide personal information, for example through online forms, email requests, or forums, we will use that information only for the purpose for which you provide it and for the purpose of detecting abuse of this website.

We use an abuse detection system called Mollom which reports illegal use of this website to the website administrator. Details of that web service’s privacy policy are available on the [Mollom website](http://mollom.com/web-service-privacy-policy). Aside from to our abuse detection system, we will not disclose any personal information you provide to a third party without your permission.

Any forums, wikis, blogs and other social media hosted by the Ministry for the Environment will have their own privacy and security statements which you should read before taking part.

The Ministry will hold all information you provide in accordance with the Privacy Act 1993.

If you would like to access and/or correct any personal information we hold, please contact:

Privacy Officer  
Ministry for the Environment  
PO Box 10362  
Wellington 6143  
New Zealand

or email[ info@mfe.govt.nz](mailto:info@mfe.govt.nz).

## Submissions and privacy concerns 

Some parts of this website allow you to make submissions on a variety of topics. If you choose to make a submission, the Ministry for the Environment may publish all or part of any submission on this website. We will consider you to have consented to such publishing by making a submission, unless you indicate otherwise on the online submission form in the boxes provided.

Information supplied in submissions is subject to the Official Information Act 1982 (OIA). Copies of submissions made to the Ministry for the Environment will normally be released in full in response to an OIA request received from a member of the public. If you object to the release of information contained in your submission, please clearly state this in your submission (in the ‘Objections to release of information’ box), including which part(s) you consider should be withheld, together with the reason(s) for withholding the information. We will take into account all such objections when responding to requests for copies of, and information on, submissions to this document.
